I'm G to have uh some of the viewers
play a drinking game of how many times
Matias says here's a tip during this
episode people are going to be like
wasted as heck after
[Music]
that
so so before we started this episode I
was like all right man tell me how to
how to pronounce your your name give it
give it to me now because I'm not gonna
get it
right you mean my handle yeah a lean and
and that means what it it means like you
want someone to fall down a well
and dude I don't know why do we have the
weirdest handles man mine is like some
freaking like video game gun from when I
was like 12 and you're telling people to
fall down a well that's well that's
lovely man but there's there's a little
story to that it's like uh that was like
something that a friend of mine or an ex
colleague of mine used to say as a as
like an insult because he's from up
North and apparently they say it there
and so I was I was signing up for some
service I don't forget which one it was
might have been Gmail but it could have
been something else too and it was might
have been Gmail yeah yeah but it's like
oh that's taken oh that's taken oh
that's taken so I just put that in and I
like you know what this is never going
to be taken anywhere I'm sticking to it
dude that's that's freaking great man
and so you named yourself yeah in
English there's like um you know go jump
in a lake is what people or jump off a
cliff or something like that people will
say um that's hilarious that you put
that as your name um well dude welcome
to the Pod with that lovely start
welcome to the Pod and um thanks for
coming on it's uh you know one of the
things that I love about podcasting
is that you kind of get to catch up with
people a little bit like I'm I'm kind of
bad at like keeping up with all my bug
Bounty friends and I haven't I mean we
haven't spoken in like man it's probably
been almost five years maybe maybe four
years um so H how have you been man what
have you been up to why why haven't you
been at the live hacking
events
uh I don't know it's a long story I got
kind of burned out I guess around
2020 or around when Corona hit
anding events stopped yeah and then I
also at some other issues like in my
life my relationship wasn't going
anywhere and we broke up and then
instead of handling it I started playing
World of
Warcraft classic classic move right
there oh man so I I found some
interesting stuff in in like
the you hacking World of
Warcraft yeah well they didn't let me do
some stuff in like
add on that I wanted to but
you that's great man well you know I I
will say the
um uh the burnout thing is something
that's real real real you know like
pretty much everyone who's on the live
hacking event circuit deals with it and
especially if you're you know you're
doing every event for a little while
like you were um it it becomes a lot um
but you you were actually did you you
came to Vegas this year and you guys won
right
yeah yeah that's a good comebacking yeah
now oh dang it move your head a little
bit to the side is that two is that two
belts I see up there Dam freaking people
you know for a little while it was it
was me and frons with the with the two
belts and I was like all right you know
I can I can be I can be happy with this
and now the number has has grown
substantially and now I got to like get
my [__] together and and get another
belt so bummer man well yeah I would
have loved to have been in Vegas this
year and seen you but but you know such
is life and now we get to catch up here
so that works well um yeah so I guess
2020 burnout a little bit stopped doing
bug Bounty period for a while or what
yeah basically the only thing I did
2021 and two was like
helping some people who asked me
questions so I got like a couple of uh
collaboration reports but other than
that nothing yeah dude that uh that that
was a underrated Revenue stream for me
as a uh as a podcaster because what'll
happen is you know people will message
me and and like let me just also put
this out there for the people that are
listening I will definitely help with
bugs but they need to be actual bugs you
know they need to be actually good leads
right so people will message me sometime
and they'll be like hey I I've got this
uh you know EX XS I can't quite figure
out but clearly you know we're escaping
the xss context and there's a valid you
know xss here we just got to like get
around this WAFF or we've got to like
you know code golf in some some exploit
um and I love that and it's been a great
it's been you know people I I think on
average I've made like two or three k a
month from like people reaching out to
me since I've launched the podcast being
like hey exploit this so it definitely
does help when you're you know well
known for your exploitation
capabilities yeah I I want to give a tip
actually about collaboration yeah and
and also what I've been doing this past
week with some friends yeah I think that
another thing that's super
underestimated is to try to become maybe
expert in this is the wrong word but
really knowledgeable about a specific
technology or like development stack or
some area and then you can talk to
people who specialize in like a couple
of different programs and maybe they
they can just like search their verbs
like yeah they use a blah blah blah
thing here and you can get
like paid for that research across all
of the programs too yeah and and this is
something that that um you know we've
had nogi on the podcast a couple times
or well I guess we've had him at least
once um but there's more to come uh and
and he you know he does a great job with
this is like he's got an automation
setup that's you
know pretty much one of the best around
and uh you know people will hit him up
and be like hey I've got the zero day
and he'll just you know help everyone
exploit it across all the all the
programs and uh help everyone you know
sort of tie up those loose ends and get
a get a cut of it so you know it's great
on on the on the distributor side and
it's also great on the researcher side
too um and definitely yeah that's a
that's a great tip and under
underestimated way to make a good chunk
in bug Bounty I
think yeah yeah for sure the the the um
yeah yeah it it's and and on top of that
you know you get if you're doing quality
research you know you get access to the
research as well you know you you're
you're doing quality research that you
can release and it's good for you know
publicity and that sort of thing um but
the catch there is you've got to find
something that's widely used so it's
it's a little bit tricky because you
know if you if you go down this rabbit
hole and you research something and then
it's not widely used you know you'll be
like oh I found this crazy bug and then
there's like three companies that use it
or something like that yeah is pretty
funny I've had I've had a lot of those
too like I yeah I found a I I found
a pre off RC in
a open source project oh my go that like
a company put out which had uh a bug
Bund program yeah but I couldn't find an
instance that they were using it
themselves what yeah so it was probably
just some internal system or behind vpan
or whatever somewhere so I reported it
to them and they were like ah we don't
think this is such a big deal and I got
like not that much how do you a preo rce
is not a big deal hey man don't ask me
but I I put I put in like a signature in
my automation there
uh but I've I I found a couple of them
but since it's patched now like every
time I see that pop up I'm like Dam that
sucks man you know when I did it it is
and when I did the graphon bug in um
in 2020 I had a um pre Off full read
ssrf on grafana that like popped me like
70 companies or something ridiculous
like that it was like and and it was
just always straight to the AWS metadata
too because everyone always spins it up
in AWS right um and I was like okay you
know I've I I've kind of sprayed this
around and then I finally released it
and and um you know before I did I
really like somebody told me like hey I
think it was nafy I think nafy hit me up
and was like Hey man um I'm pretty sure
gitlab has like an embedded version of
grafana in it right and I was like oh my
gosh you know and and it was vulnerable
to that too so you could like hit hit up
uh you know any gitlab instance that was
publicly facing was also vulnerable um
so it's also I think another good tip
for that is like if you can take take a
piece of software and see if other
pieces of software are um are actually
utilizing that as a part of their stack
uh you even if it's full applications
like grafana being embedded inside a
gitlab then sometimes you can pop an
additional set of of phones there yeah
and it does like what the even better
Point yeah or if you can manage to find
it is to find like insecure defaults or
ways of setting it up in an insecure way
because then it won't it probably won't
be even touched yeah so now you're
sitting on something that will will not
like have an end end of life yeah dude
insecure defaults is is huge man that
would be yeah looking into that and then
spraying it spraying it wide is is a
great idea um you mentioned a second ago
your automation setup and so I've got it
you know here on our little on our
little uh dock our very our dock that
all of a sudden became very very long as
I've stalked you over the past five
years to to consolidate all of the
content that you've produced down into
uh into one podcast um but so I know you
have a little bit of a origin with asset
note right um you know when asset note
was just a baby uh you were kind of sort
of involved in that so I'd like to hear
about that and then I'd also like to
hear about what your automation setup
looks like
nowadays yeah so when it comes to as
note and I guess the same is true for
detectify later like yeah I don't think
that anything is left of my
contributions like to like an actual
product and everything
um but back in the day let's say what
happened was that
chubs made the first like J version of
asset note and put it open source and
then that project kind of died and I was
interested in building something similar
so I found this project and I asked him
just straight up hey is there any like P
request that you didn't merge or like
code that you didn't commit can you can
you do it because I'm going to get and
do something with this yeah can I have
any free code please yeah yeah I mean
like if there was bu and you to fix them
can I exactly this is a great I love
this
question yeah no but then it was like
really excited that someone took an
interest to it I suppose and we started
building it
together um until uh until I guess he or
we realized that it became an effective
enough
solution I guess that could actually be
turned into a real valuable product yeah
and so then we forked again and I I
chose to keep my version which is like I
rewrote almost all of it too so now it's
like we converged and we did
whatever I know I know that he credits
you a lot with um you know some of the
momentum that he had with uh with Asin
note in the beginning I'm sure with that
um you know initial interest sort of
Reviving the project and then also like
something about project man you know he
was on the episode like like there was
some sort of like project management
help they needed or something like that
and then you guys helped them out with
that I don't know what that was but I I
it's it must feel great to be uh a part
of such a big you know thing because
like I don't know I don't know if you
feel the same way but I have like so
much respect for the people at at AET
note you know what they built
technically and also just to see shub
you know and the whole team really Sean
as well and and and all them you know
being in our hacker groups and then
going and building like this massive you
know uh product that is used by so many
companies nowadays and just kind of
taking that entrepreneurial route so
that's got to be pretty cool yeah for
sure it's awesome I love shs and those
guys they're great people and hackers
yeah for sure so your automation you
said you've mostly Rewritten it um what
language are you using what kind of
stuff are you doing now in this that
you're excited
about it's still python
Andress
and yeah no it's just simple I I I like
simple code so I like the less complex
it is the more beautiful it is and that
goes for systems code or networks or
whatever that's like my point of view of
anything technical dude so it just it's
it has not
no no out scalability no weird [__] it
just collects data and that's about it
and does its job and sticks it in a
database I love that man you know that
that's really underrated um you know
I've talked about it on the pot a couple
times before but I um I have I was in
the Recon game for a long time and like
here and there nowadays I'll kind of
think about like H you know maybe I'll
go back to that real quick and like just
kind of see if I can at least get my
instance sort of spun up again and get
some host monitoring in place and that
sort of thing and then I go back and I
look at the code and I'm like this is so
freaking complex and and even you know
even uh one of the guys in the the uh
golden actually in the ctbb Discord he
uh he was asking me you know hey you
know how do we deal with wild cards wild
card subdomains and how do we filter out
you know the stuff that's not a wild
card in inside the Wild Card definition
right and I I gave him I gave him like
this whole piece of code which works you
know in my defense it does work really
well and and it does filter out uh the
wild cards quite well but it's like it
was like 500 600 lines of code just to
filter out a wild card you know and um
and so yeah I I think it's a struggle to
keep your code that simple and if you
can it's like so beautiful and helpful
for
automation yeah no for sure for sure
yeah and then like another tip there I
maybe like maybe I'm not up to date with
a Recon game because people building
such Advanced awesome stuff but um one
thing that I think it might be
underrated and this is only based on
that I found them and I've been
surprised that like why don't people do
this it's just that if you're going to
do headless browser stuff like for
screenshots for example anyway then you
might as well all the the network logs
or the DNS logs because I've seen a lot
of places where people
have like maybe it's not on get slash or
maybe it's on some other page but they
they will make some kind of external
resource request whether it's an image
or like a script or something else to a
domain that's either has a takeover or
that's just like you can just buy the
domain and dude what the heck man
freaking Matias coming up the pot being
like okay guys you know I don't know if
this is up up to par for the Pod but
like and I've been doing this I I have
been talking about this [__] for like
four years and I have not once ever
thought to do that when you've already
got it loaded up in the browser anyway
all of the resources are already
resolving Maas dude that's genius what
the heck
guys go do this all of you now see this
is the problem you're about to learn
after this episode because you say stuff
on the Pod right and then you know
people actually listen to it and then
they go do stuff and now your secrets
are gone too so I should have I should
have warned you you know before this
episode but I appreciate you dropping
that awesome tip because I'm sure that
will lead to many many takeovers and
many many vones for lots of targets so
that's a that's a freaking great tip man
um yeah I I want to give tips like it's
it's a good challenge to just put stuff
out there I think France noted it too
but like yeah it's good to get get your
secrets out there because then you need
to get new and that motivates you to to
research I guess yeah I'm I'm glad you
both have that that mentality that's
really beneficial for
me um yeah but but on that point though
there's there's different ways to
publish your research too I guess
because I I'm not very good
at writing blog post or maybe I'm good
at it but I don't do it freaking frons
just like pumps him out man like what
the heck yeah no he's a beast like the
same with the
like writing reports like yeah he he
could be like one of those people what
are they called like when you're in
court and you have to fight really fast
yeah I don't know what those things are
called it could be one of those if like
this bug thing is going is it a
stenographer yeah yeah stenographer
that's it that's the word yeah dude but
he I mean it's crazy and I was looking
at in prep for the episode with him I
was looking at like the history of
research that he's kind of put out over
the past you know for forever and um and
I missed you know I had like a full list
of like eight or nine or 10 I was like
man this guy puts out so much research
and then we get in the episode and he's
like oh yeah I wrote about this in that
blog and this blog and that blog that I
didn't have in the list and I was like
you are just like a freaking you know
writing machine so yeah that's very
impressive and let me tell you Maas man
podcasting is great can I highly
recommend podcasting if you don't like
writing reports because you can just get
on the Pod you know you don't have to do
multiple takes or whatever and you don't
have to like refine your your thing like
you do on YouTube and you get to just
sit down chat you know be authentic with
the people and you know you get that
information out there so maybe we'll
have to make you like a like a
reoccurring guest on the podcast or
something yeah maybe maybe that's S I
mean another thing is like another
benefit of sharing is that if you're not
very good at
storing your information I mean you have
it in your brain obviously but
it's it's like you get an archive of
your stuff you don't it yeah go go back
and if if you can deal with listening to
your own voice right like I I um I
listen to the Pod every single week the
the critical thinking podcast every week
just for like quality assurance purposes
and just to like make sure it's hitting
you know the standards and that sort of
thing that I want and in the beginning
it was like nails on a chalkboard man it
was like making me want to uh what is it
I've leading Brun likeing me want to
jump in a well man and uh and and um and
yeah but after after you know a couple
episodes I kind of that kind of wore off
a little bit and now it's not as uh not
as terrible unless I laugh you know and
then I'm just like what the heck is that
laugh Justin what are you what are you
what are you doing um but yeah it does
help and also when you talk about it and
you and you teach it you know or you
discuss it with somebody it concretes it
a little bit more in your head and we
were talking about this you know before
we we we started the recording but we've
all got that sort of technical context
window of sorts right so like you deep
dive a specific piece of content you
know of of research and then like you're
super excited about it you've got it all
in your head and then if somebody asks
you a question about that three months
later it's like oh man I swear I knew
the answer to this question you know so
but if you get out there and you talk
about it it sticks a little bit better
yeah I I had that this just like
yesterday or if it was two days ago okay
it's so backstory France and I have
teamed up a little
bit with Tano and Jonathan bman oh man
oh gosh that combination man holy crap
yeah we we found good stuff we started
like last Friday or something um but
anyway we we found something that looked
like
a Dynam
DB injection yeah and I I was like I
should know is because this summer so
I'm helping out with u running and
building CF challenges for a Swedish CF
called I mean it's on CF and I made like
a Dynam DB CF challenge oh did you
really so at the time I had like at
least to me novel research and stuff to
do with damic DB right right but now
when it came up just a few months later
it was
like I have no
idea what that was yeah dude that's so
discouraging and then you're like you
know all right I got to like go back in
my notes and then you're like ah [__] I
don't have any notes and then you're
like you're just trying to piece it all
back together but the good thing is at
least you know that that I think um you
you do have you know those neural
Pathways sort of primed of sorts right
and and it does become easier to re
access those once you you've done it but
it is disappointing when you you feel
like you should know something off right
off the top of your head and it's not
and it's not there
um yeah for sure yeah all right all
right let me get back to this um let me
get back to this this dock here you
mentioned something you know about about
collaboration a second you know when we
were talking about collaboration and I
think you did a great talk um about this
uh and I'm trying to see if I can find
the link to the YouTube I I I took like
uh like six screenshots of this YouTube
video and then I didn't actually uh save
the video to my uh to to my dock here so
we'll link it down in the description
below but you did a talk at I believe it
was an oasp um conference a while back
talking about about collaboration and
mentioning that you know you this sort
of um concept of bounty Effectiveness
and how collaboration sort of affects
that right you know you increase the
number of bugs found you decrease the
risk of duplicates you you uh you know
decrease the time taken because of how
you know you're getting sort of double
time right um and I love this concept
man of like creating and we were kind of
talking about it last week on the Pod
with with uh Joel and and Sam even
though they were kind of [__] on my
idea of like you know trying to minimize
bug Bounty down to like a function of
how many attack vectors or reasonable
attack vectors is what I should have
said that you try on a Target you know
over time um but I I just kind of wanted
to brainstorm a little bit on this
together um this concept of like like
how can
we formula formul formula eyes turn into
a formula uh that you know bug Bounty
right and so I I've got this concept
around like taking optimizing for time
spent actually trying reasonable attack
factors um and then you've got this
concept of like calculating bugs found
times risk of duplicates SL time taken
or you know divided by time taken
results in your Effectiveness um have
you had any sort
of evolution in this formula or
evolution in your bu bug Bounty
optimization Journey over the past you
know I think it was five years ago that
you did this
talk uh I'm not sure like on a high
level I think that's still true because
the end goal at least for me with bug PP
is is the same the only things that have
changed is that there there's been some
additional factors added I guess to the
time taken so for
example I'm going to take hack one for
example but I'm sure the other platforms
do too like they try to encourage you to
use like the CVS as a system yeah like
that takes more of your time and more
programs are using uh like Dyer Services
which unfortunately sometimes uh takes
more of your time yeah um so those are
like two sub parts of time that you can
try to optimize too yeah yeah trying to
trying to identify programs that will
triage efficiently and and are capable
with their own products I think is is
definitely a big thing um I wanted to
get your thoughts on this okay
so I I I hate to even bring this up
again man because every single time I
say anything negative about
collaboration people kind of like [__]
on me a little bit uh but the risk of
duplicates thing that you talked about
here you said that went down when you
were working with you know frons or
working with any other collaborator
right um the ri my my qualm with that
piece of your formula is that I think
there would be overlap you know
everybody's going to find that basic
idore and instead of getting you know a
one in X portion of the bounty you're
getting one of x divided by two now
because you're
you're collaborating with your you know
your your friend and you're only getting
half of one portion of that of that bug
so I feel like your risk of duplicates
as it pertains to your actual Bounty
amount issued this is largely within a
within a um live hacking man context
obviously because we're talking about
dupke Windows um yeah uh you know I feel
like that kind of affects the output of
your of your Bounty so how how do you
think about that and and what is your
what is your response to that
I mean I guess I agree with you when it
comes to things that you expect everyone
else for everyone to find yeah uh but
for the most part it's still better to
get 1% of something than 0% of something
so yeah yeah I I I suppose that's true
and I guess also you know you and um you
and and France and and you know your
collaboration team you know when they've
been bigger in the past you guys are
less focusing on I think volume of
reports and more focusing on like okay
we found this thing that just blew up
you know blew up the
whole program right and you find these
crazy RC's and then you're you know
you're just splitting your you know 40K
50k you know two ways or or four ways or
whatever and that that feels a little
bit better yeah for sure I I think
that if you don't like duplicat then you
should go deep because like I I I
started Bounty again like March I think
or if it was April this year and I've
had zero duplicates and like around a
bucks wow dude man you guys are tearing
it up I know I've been talking to fron a
little bit you know the the program that
you guys have been working on um you
know I assume it's that program is is
that one yeah um it's like 95% that
program
I just I cannot believe the volume of
bounties you guys have pulled from that
program this year like unbelievable uh
it it's it's the most amount of money
I've ever seen anyone earn in bug Bounty
and that is uh in in one year and that
includes like these
Recon Gods out there that are just
automating everything um and you guys
are doing it manual so that's kind of
nuts you you are doing it almost
entirely manual right yeah I mean we
have some program specific stuff that
you we try to automate like wow okay
this this type of pattern seem to emerge
at multiple places so we should try to
look after that automatically if we can
with like some turble Intruder or
something can you can you elaborate any
more on that or your your lip sealed for
now on the on that specifics well no not
not specifics but like like you don't
need leak your your secrets but like you
know are you looking for routes are you
looking for you know is it an
authorization problem you know give the
people a little juice I guess actually
there's another tip for yeah like
Automation and I know some people do it
but it's a good idea to have program or
category specific signatures let's say
or
uh without a bunch of jaml files
um um why can't I think of it right now
it's contagious whatever you uh nuclei
right is that what you're talking about
yeah yeah yeah like think of it
as nuclear templates custom to
that program let say
100% yeah that makes sense uh so and I
also think that this is something
that's yeah I have a big problem with
like automatically repeating in verb
it's a some can someone please make make
a good verp extension for that okay so
hold on there there are some extensions
what what do you mean by automatically
repeating it I me with a specific mod
modification yes if if the request
contains this then just like give me the
whole request I rewrite it with my
python or whatever code and then send it
and then if contains this in the
response like give me a heads up I'm
about to change your life man uh there
there is a there is a plugin called
aoriz that that does this and there's
also another it doesn't work for
everything uh it doesn't okay so you you
You' played around with this
before yes I tried that and I tried Auto
repeater and I've tried there was a
couple more and none of them can just
like give me the whole raw request that
to make changes to it and but but I know
that that burp what is called Montoya
API has support for that so yeah now I'm
using like a there was someone
in B forum who posted like a turbo
Intruder hack to it I guess that can
just like monitor all the requests from
proxy and then you can actually uh
rewrite it I can link to that wow yeah
yeah definitely link to that well if you
shoot that over to me afterwards I'll um
let me grab a notepad here uh a but but
turbo Intruder isn't perfect either
because the turbo Intruders like output
window is like not standard no component
so so I you know I spent the whole day
just trying to make like a f red dude we
need we need freaking uh Chachi PT to
like ingest the matoya API docks so you
can just uh do that but also I I'm just
gonna say you know and also I want to
clarify on this pod I I I love burp I
really do I talk about Kao all the time
and I talk about the problems of burp
the port swiger in general absolutely
amazing company the search they put out
the product is phenomenal it's it's
amazing I also am a big fan of kaido
kaido is is one of the things that
they're working on right now I know is
pretty much the ability to to do exactly
what you just talked about and it's just
to to have every request sort of shell
out to a python script or something like
that and I just think wow how beautiful
is that you know how simple and
beautiful would that be if like because
most of us can do basic coding anyway
right if you're going to be you know
using an HTTP proxy and stuff like that
sure they the exceptions of like people
that really just are business logic
people and just focus primarily on HTTP
and that sort of thing but um most of us
can like you know code in bash or code
in python or something like that and the
ability to just shell out you know to to
Python and modify the request and then
send it through and then alert on
anything that you know comes back that's
going to be golden and it's just going
to be so easy to extend so I'm really
I'm really looking forward to that yeah
and to to me I
about Port but it's like we had we have
like the kind of same issue with I guess
the reversing Community had with Ida and
and the x-rays where just like well I
guess they're the best so so they get to
decide yeah exactly so I I like I
haven't tried k k yeah but I like the
concept
of competition in the space yeah me too
and and um I I've got it open right now
I'm actually looking at it on my other
monitor and um and yeah I've switched my
workflow over entirely to kaido now um
there are still a couple things that I
have to do manually and that are kind of
bothersome but they've made promises to
me that they're fixing it you know next
uh next version um and I've I've just
found I found uh well into the you know
five figures range of of Bounties in the
past month with uh with kaido so it's
definitely working for me
um which is good and also they they sent
me a little I don't know if I'm going to
get in trouble with them for for leaking
this but they sent me a little uh a
video of the search functionality that
they're implementing which has like a
very
um uh wire shark esque uh sort of query
language that you can use uh and it's
just very simple you type it up in the
in the you know in a search bar up at
the top and it just it works it works
fast it's it's clean and easy for you to
to write you know compound queries and
that sort of thing and I'm just so
freaking excited for that um so that
should be great you can open like a
search window and then it searches
through everything with that it's like
loger Plus+ yeah well it it is yeah and
and but um actually I haven't used
logger Plus+ in as much detail um but
the thing that I'm really excited for is
the query language right you being able
to you know you can just put plain you
know text in there and it'll it'll
search for it as well you know in the
body or whatever but also which is very
useful but also you know having being
able to do compound queries and be like
okay when the host header looks like
this and this cookie is set in the
response you know like you know that
sort of thing um it will I think will be
I really missed that in bir too like I
really wish they at least had like a
group bu function BP search yeah yeah no
for or for sure you know what what I
would like in like a
attacking proxy or whatever we should
call the tools yeah give me an API or
like a DAT database connection something
let me query the data that is in there
don't make me export it to some you
know crappy XML based format and then
yeah dude me me too man and actually um
I was I was fussing at uh c one of the
Developers for kaido the other day I was
like please implement this feature and
he's like dude that's such a pain and
like just code it yourself and he gave
me like he said all right this these are
the graphql API requests that you need
to do it and just like you do this in
the meantime until I get around to
implementing this and um I haven't gone
and done it yet because I've been busy
with some stuff this past week but once
they release the docs for the graphql
API as well that powers
kaido that is going to be big time
helpful um so definitely definitely
looking forward to
that um all right man well we we got
down a little a little path there love
love talking about kaido um let's see
where where do I want to go from here um
so before we get into some of the more
technical stuff cuz I want to ask you
some questions about uh mutation xss and
some xss challenges that you've been
putting out recently um I want to hear
about detectify and your experience with
that because essentially the the story
as fron told it yeah was you know this
young whipper snapper comes into his uh
whatever like Commerce company or
whatever it was and he's sitting in the
corner ARP spoofing everybody in the
office um and doing hacking stuff and
then you know France walks up and he's
like wow you know this this guy's a
genius and we got to let him do what
he's you know best at which is security
related stuff and uh you know you guys
started detectify together and I'm sure
that's a little bit of a
misrepresentation of the story you know
from my memory and from France's memory
but I want to hear it's a little bit
it's a little bit like The Edge on the
story but sure sure I want to hear your
side of it and tell me how uh how you
and fron originally met cuz you guys are
like the in my opinion you guys are the
most prolific like the most well-known
hacking Duo that just like destroys
everything they touch essentially when
you guys hack together um and when you
hack individually too so you know
obviously when you put it together it's
going to be be better um so I want to
hear about that origin story sure
so the origin of detectify goes back to
before that actually so oh really yeah I
I can I can try to fast forward my
origin story when it comes to hacking
yeah yeah pleas
I met the Alm rout that
alout when I was super young like we
were like seven and eight years old or
something MH yeah and when we were 12
and 13 we started programming or trying
to understand
programming um and we
fell
into
analyzing like Windows vbscript malw
Word so as you do yeah I don't know I
don't know where the idea come from but
we did and so the first programming
language like scripting language or
whatever you should call it that I I
Learned was vit script actually and I I
still remember to this day that was like
the first time I had this WOW feeling
that that I still get today when hacking
because it took I think it
took three days or something of just
staring at this BB script and like it
was so foreign to me it was just text
but then suddenly I I understood like
the concept of a variable oh man and
that's what I like and that's when
everything changed that is when
everything changed but anyway past for a
couple years we start
finding like hacking RC networks and uh
war game sites and uh like forums and
stuff like this and starting learning it
security and web security it
was
somewhat how do you say it did exist but
it was still kind of in in its infancy
if you compare it to today yeah and
uh and fast forward a little bit more
and the concept of defacements started
to
popularized I guess we're getting a
whole you know web security history
right now man this is great okay we
going way back we're getting to
defacements people are like overwriting
websites and stuff okay all right hit me
yeah and then there was this like sites
that compiled the the like Zone age was
one of them yeah yeah yeah and and we
kind of during that time we had some
weird Insight or like it was from like
the old old school hacker Community
where it's like read the [__] manual
and like do everything yourself in some
kind of way yeah so we didn't use any
like
external I mean we used the operating
system of course but we tried to build
everything ourselves dude what the heck
why are you having to specify that he
like because if I say we buildt
everything ourselves someone in the
comment is going to be oh yeah did you
so her
that yeah no no you're 100% right no I I
I just love that that was how far down
you went you know you're like oh yeah
you know we used the operating system of
course but everything else was manual
that's that's sick so so this is a great
you know now that's a great thing to
highlight though because that's one of
the best ways to learn all of this stuff
is like implementing it yourself and
then after that if somebody's tool Does
It Better You Know use their tool but if
you you having implemented it you know
yourself will really assure that you
understand everything about it and
that's something that I've done many of
times and and why don't really
um why I tell people to write their own
automation stuff rather than using all
of you know some of the these great
tools out there sometimes you know at
least in the beginning uh because it'll
help you understand the Core Concepts
and understand where optimizations can
be made so it's cool that you did that
too for sure for sure and I think that
it's a good exercise for anyone to like
take an RC and try build an
implementation of it yeah and then
you'll and you'll come to realize that
okay this is
just code like anything else it's not
magic yeah 100% but but in any case we
joked around about
this compilation defacement sites
because a lot of people what they did
was they went to like milworm or similar
places where public exploits were
published and they just took it and like
copy pasted it on a bunch of places so
we were like yeah well that's not
hacking classic scrip Kitty [__] right
there we we can build a program that's
better than that yeah was kind of
there oh and that's
detected yeah that was like the absolute
first version of detectify and it didn't
even it wasn't called detectify until so
is this pre pre this was pre you joining
the company with
fron yeah this how old were you at this
point we were 17 and 18 17 and 18 okay
gotcha nice so you but you've already
been doing this for a while when did you
first start getting interested in it
security stuff that was like 13 or 14
yeah yeah same same age here so that
that's something you see pretty early
and and I know you're like a you know
you're like a Timeless elf over there
you still look exactly the same you know
and everyone's like ah you know yeah
he's like 18 when we you know first met
you but it's you know it's it's
different um and and you've got a bunch
of context on the early bug Bounty sort
of space and what it looked like when it
first came out and you remember being
involved in that the beginning um yeah
so I'm going to ask you questions about
that later but first I want you to
finish your story here so you know you
start building the early early versions
of detectify because you're like okay we
can make like a better version of this
um you know and code it ourselves where
we Implement our own you know exploits
or whatever and um and so you know how
did that how did that integrate with
with France and Fran's company or
wherever you were at at the time when
you started working with him so we had a
friend in the our high school I don't
know how to translate that but the
school you go to when you're 18 and you
graduate at 18 in Sweden but uh we had a
friend who who had a job at like Francis
and his business partners company
programmer so we were like University
that sounds boring you can get a job
already if you know programming we we
know programming we can write BB script
yeah actually we graduated through
bb.net during these times o nice and
maybe hot tap I don't I'm not sure I
still think that we should Studio not
called studio is it's the best ID that
I've ever used in the year I'm sorry
what what
id Visual Studio A Visual Studio yeah no
100% I'm you know I I was a Vim boy for
a long time and you know obviously I
still use Vim daily but um Joel sat me
down one time when we were PA hacking
was like all right Justin
close
everything install visual code you know
vs code right now and we're going to set
some things up and that changed my life
so and even right now with the um with
the word fence uh sponsorship that we
did last week um you know I've been
using vs code and I've been there's like
a a way that you can hook into Docker
containers that are running right and so
and it's like one click it's so easy and
so you install the docker extension you
know and then it just shows all the
docker instances you've got up and you
just click attach to visual studio code
and now you're inside that Docker
container modifying the the the plugin
you know code for for WordPress inside
that container and it's like oh man this
is so easy I freaking love it yeah no no
for sure we should okay sorry I have to
make the distinction no I meant I meant
we shall still and that is different oh
dude get out of here get get get out no
you're off the Pod now what what what do
you mean Visual Studio I I can't even
fathom that that was what you meant
what but but yeah I use wish Studio code
for like everything now but it when I
was doing the coding inet framework of
course yeah use that and it has an a I
haven't tried it for a long time now but
I really like the debugger in the race I
think it's called and you do like you
can just jump around in Threads and you
can like go into a thread and like uh
drag dro the program counter and like
change stuff it was good that's awesome
but anyway no that's cool all right
continue continue your story sorry so we
started working um as developers at
Francis company I guess and we also had
discussions I don't know how it came up
let's just say that we were in a corner
and doing airp yeah exactly or
something and uh we presented the
scanner
actually we had this pretty funny the
first time we were GNA demo the scanner
France built like an application and he
like purchas implanted a seal injection
somewhere and we had made some like
stupid change to the scanner like a few
like a week before that they're like oh
wouldn't it be funny if you play videos
inside of it and then like B yeah I
don't know it was so we basically the
whole thing rck roll him or something
like
that no we broke we broke it so we're
like oh [__] we should have used control
uh but we can rewrite this my we wrote
we wrote the whole thing and uh it
didn't find the bug yeah well the
purpose of it was not to find bugs that
you know exist in the OR at least as far
as I understand it it's not like
crawling endpoints looking for SQL
injection it's like oh it was it was
done oh it was that okay cool
interesting that's cool yeah so we we
were thinking of competing with like
this big I think one of them was called
like IBM rational app scan like super
Enterprise Products was which was doing
basically that but there wasn't any
players that
we could find at least in like the low
medium siiz space so that was like the
original pitch but then it's like
shifted Through The Years so now it's
they have this uh
monitoring thing and not much but back
then it was but then we talked with
friends and his his business associate
and was like okay we'll we'll we'll
found a company together wow that's
awesome man so so the from there you
guys you know launched detectify and and
are you still involved with that product
or are you kind of hands offish now I'm
super hands off I if there
some research that I think can be
implemented the product I submitted via
the crowdsource platform oh so you just
like use the product you know as a
researcher like every now and then I
I'll visit the office and stuff but yeah
but I'm I'm just a I'm just some guy now
so so I mean let me ask then you know
did you exit that
company like intentionally or did is
there some reason you you don't want to
work a you know in in an entrepreneurial
role or or are you in an entrepreneurial
role now you know what what are you
doing for your for your primary income
source so there was two questions there
yeah
like okay let's see if I can finish the
story oh no and I cut off your story too
all right I'm sorry go ahead yeah we
start building detective
I we make some decisions to build it
like uh
traditional startup at the time oh and
at some point uh bug b as a concept in
like web space space uh started popping
up like Google and like Facebook and
PayPal and some others had programs uh
which which paid money and a bunch of
others side which paid like t-shirts or
sure other stuff and uh yeah we we saw
that as an opportunity
to get like a foot on bigger clients
because if we could had a blog post
saying like oh we have Google then maybe
it's okay that we don't have Google as
like a reference customer per se and U
yeah that actually did
work we see that time and time again in
the bug Bounty world yeah so that was
kind of like a a a two purpose thing
with bu Bounty so me France Me and Al
started doing
it back then
so so yeah that was a fun time no
platforms and wild west yeah dude that
that I've got a bunch of questions about
you know sort of OG bugani stuff and you
you mentioned you
know you made some predictions about bu
Bounty which I think were really
accurate um you know in a talk a couple
years back so we'll swing back to that
in a second um but yeah so I
guess H have you considered full-time
Bounty or are you know do you want to be
an entrepreneur do you want to work for
a company you know what does that
decision look like for you as somebody
who's clearly skilled enough in bug
bounty to make it work you know
full-time so I did try fulltime bug
bount actually for three months just as
I left the techi and yeah like I left
the techi because I didn't like the way
the company was going become two
Enterprise two American startup and
there was just some decision that
I did didn't feel like it was going
right so I decided Well I I'm gonna work
I'm gonna do something else actually I
decided I'm gonna do bike BPS inad nice
okay and I did for like three months
until I just found myself one day like
what day is it why don't I care I to get
some in my life 100% man yeah so
and uh like there's some people who can
do it and like props too but ever since
after those three months I've been I've
had like a part-time employment so so
I've been working as a traditional
pentester I've been working with like
security training I've been working like
blue blue team also had done like some
freelance projects but it's all always
been something to keep me at B yeah no
that that makes a lot of sense man I
mean the structure thing is one of the
hardest things about full-time bug
Bounty and like especially for the
people that have the skills to to make
it to make it actually work from a
financial perspective like they almost
all have the
tendency myself included you know
to just dive into it head first like no
you you
know no restraint you know and just you
know wake up and be like wait what what
day is this you know you know you know
all all I can think about is XYZ you
know um and so that's definitely one of
the most common common pitfalls uh that
you that you see and it's as you pointed
out it's it's really unhealthy and it's
one of the things you got to beat if you
want to do it you know full-time in the
long term and and you know it's like you
pointed out it's something that you need
to shut off you know and you need to go
back to part-time employment or
full-time employment if you can't
because it's just too destructive you
know um and so I'm glad you had that
that wisdom to go down that
path yeah know for sure that's uh I
might try again at some point when I'm
older and wiser but yeah that's that's
kind of like I I really enjoy it having
like that so yeah and I can also like if
there's like a hacking coming out or
like a new program or something that I'm
super interested in I can just take time
off and then and be a degenerate for
like a couple of weeks and then go back
to yeah exactly no no that that makes a
lot of sense man I think at some point
you know maybe I'll brainstorm a little
bit about this afterwards but I know
that there are a couple people that I
know that are doing full-time book
Bounty that are still struggling with
this whole thing and and I am too you
know I mentioned a couple weeks back on
the Pod how how um you know how burnt I
felt and like you trying to restart that
passion for hacking after going going
away from it for a little while to do
some traveling and to do some other
things um so there's lots of struggles
that fulltime B bounty hunters have and
I'm thinking maybe I should create like
a like a little support group or
something like that in the ctbb podcast
Discord for anybody who's who's thinking
about doing full-time bug Bounty because
uh it is definitely a a challenging
environment to be a part of yeah it's no
bug Union yeah well you know that's
something everyone's talked about for
years um and actually yeah I I would be
interested to see if anybody actually
tries to to tackle that project as bug
Bounty continues to grow and it gets
attention from non bug Bounty Hunter you
know people right you know people like
lawyers and and uh you know business
people are looking at the industry and
there's opportunity there I think um uh
so yeah definitely be interested to to
see where that goes um sort of on that
note
I want to go
to some thoughts on bug Bounty and and
and history of bug Bounty and some
predictions you made uh in the past
about bug Bounty and then and then we're
going to drive uh dive into some
technical [__] um okay so first question
I had back seven years ago I had to dive
into the uh into the into the archives
for this one you said something along
the lines of this in a in a bug Crown
interview you said now I look for
programs to hack on but in the future we
will see that programs being the ones to
search for hackers to hack on their
program right um because there's just so
many programs now and there's a there is
a there's a lack of uh Talent out there
in the bug Bounty industry still and a
lot of programs are sort of having to
Vive for attention which is why we get
our inboxes blown up every single day
with like you know this company's
offering a you know whatever promotion
and you know that sort of thing um you
nailed that prediction on the head you
know years back and I'm wondering if you
have and I I know I'm putting you on the
spot so you know no is a perfectly valid
answer to this do you have any thoughts
on where the industry is headed in the
future for bug Bounty um having seen it
from the beginning you know 2012 you
know when the first when the first sort
of programs launched and that sort of
thing up to today where we've seen sort
of a flip of the tables in this regard
um yeah do you have any any thoughts on
on where it'll go or any predictions
you'd like to put on the record right
now I think
the I think there will be even
more competition for uh bounty hunters
so I think that the Bounty average
Bounty amounts will probably increase
and I think
that more programs will attempt to
make an effort to Market themselves
still it's like the same position but
even more same same POS so you're
thinking it's G still going to continue
to grow yeah because the thing is like
whether the platforms like it or not
skilled manual labor is not
scalable yeah yeah and that's what it
takes at the end of the day you know you
know PE people can do automation stuff
and you'll find bugs and that sort of
thing um and that's great and and we
need that but also at the end of the day
those are never going to you're never
going to find that weird little like you
know as fron said in in his episode that
weird little Edge case if statement that
I had to you know deduce from like three
hours of playing with an endpoint that
just destroys the whole company um you
know VI automation that's just never
going to happen um and I also hold the
position that I don't think that'll
happen with AI either um and so yeah I I
think I think it will continue to grow
just like just like said like I think
that there is some risk that is like
nonzero that The Bu the industry or
concept as a whole taking get into
trouble due to some legislation like
that's also a risk that I have thought
about in the past what do you mean when
like like oh now this count as exporting
cyber weapons you can't do that anymore
you can't do that to from the EU to the
US or whatever it may be and all of a
sudden like that's
legal that is a big risk that is
something that I hadn't really thought
of and also I I was also kind of tossing
around this idea um a while back and I
guess I'll just kind of put it out there
on the Pod now because I think I think
it would be challenging to get this
through but I thought about seeing if
you could
qualify individual vulnerabilities as
intellectual property and then have
a like a rate at which you can donate
that intellectual property the idea
would be that bug Hunters pay a lot of
taxes right um and how awesome would it
be if we could hack on nonprofits that
don't have the money to pay normal
researchers anyway donate intellectual
property to that company in the form of
a bug report and then receive a tax
write off from that
company for a standard vulnerability
amount you know for a critical 10K for a
high you know 5K or whatever and um use
that to offset some of this massive tax
buron that we've got as as
Hunters yeah no that was would be
awesome yeah we gota we got to look into
that but that's a that's a that's an
interesting point man about about
um about exporting cyber weapons I need
to I need to go look into the the risk
of that because at the end of the day
you know we've already seen that with
with China right China China already put
a thing out that says like all right
researchers you can't like like
participate in like pone or something
like that you've got to do the the
inside of China pone tone where all the
the bugs go to the government right um
at least that's what I've heard um and
so yeah there's definitely risk of that
sort of propagating I think yeah and and
like the same same is true for like
researchers from those countries like
I'm think thinking about these Russian
people who suddenly got kicked off all
platforms because like the S SS yeah no
that was the same thing like something
happens in
geopolitical world that you have nothing
to do with but it can affect you yeah
100% no I I hated the way that that they
dealt with that situation um and I don't
know whether that actually got reversed
or not cuz I meant to look into it and I
don't remember the top of my head but I
know at one point hacker one was like
okay no bounties for people in Russia
and we're donating them all of them and
I'm like what like you you're just G to
donate that money you know like no
that's not how how that works you know
if the sanctions were in place that's
fine you can't pay it out but leave it
in the hacker One account at least you
know um and so I don't know if they went
back and fixed that but if not that's a
that is very concerning um and so yeah
definitely definitely some risk there
unfortunate sitation um okay
so I guess the the other question that I
had here was what are some ways bug
bounty has changed from the
beginning of you know bug Bounty and
obviously it's changed a ton with the
with the with hacker one and Bug crowd
and integrity you know sort of coming on
the scene and creating that sort of
middleman rather than just submitting it
via email form to you know Facebook or
Google or whatever um even though we do
see some you know programs sort of
moving again away from that you know
with uh I think hack Force Salesforce
launching their own thing and and um you
know obviously Facebook is running their
own program in conjunction with some of
the big you know middlemen um so that's
cool uh but are are there any any Trends
you can see across bug Bounty history
because we we we have few few guests
that have been involved with this from
the very beginning like you you know
over 10 years ago um any Trends you're
seeing or any things you want to
highlight in bug Bounty
history I'm gonna try and make an effort
not be too negative I think I think
that's
like like a true stereotype of hackers
too like we're we love finding problems
yeah so it sounds like you so negative
but I try to find it like the positives
too so the positives is like the
platforms introduced yeah that's so so
much better you don't need like weird
Google Alerts and and trying to find out
who has a program who doesn't have a
program so that's awesome and also like
the
standardized reporting too like okay
everyone you can upload files it's on
the platform you have markdown great
and so most of the like core
functionality for hunters of the
platforms I think has been an a awesome
change from from the beginning I also
think that in general Bounty amounts
have uh gone
up so like the first rc I found for
example which it was I might be lying
now but I think it was
okay it was one of the first at least
RC's found bu but that was like $500 and
back then it was like damn
$500 yeah but this is 10 years ago too
so the you know cost of living and
inflation and that sort of thing has
gone up do is it your opinion that well
I mean I guess it hasn't gone up you
know a hundred times and you know you
can see some huge payouts for for um you
know rce nowadays so you think it's out
past it yeah for sure I I don't think
that it's just
following
inflation I think that it has G enough
due
to not entirely do thanks to the
platforms yeah but we'll get to that
Supply supply and demand as well you
know yeah yeah exactly like competition
of hunters and also like the whole
concept of B Bounty becoming
more accepted I guess on like higher
levels within organizations so it's an
easier sell today probably than than it
was back then so maybe you'll get bigger
budgets or like actually have a budget
for at all which is amazing too I have
to say because like and and obviously
you know people point this out all the
time if a program is paying $2 million a
year one of some of these big companies
$2 million a year is like you know junk
change you know like find a penny pick
it up on the ground you know to some of
these big big companies but um a lot of
these companies they're just writing a
blank check for it you know they they're
saying like all right you know that pay
what you need to pay to you know because
the researchers find stuff and I I think
that's that would have been such a hard
sell in the beginning so I'm thankful to
all the people that sort of paved the
path for that in the past because um you
know I'm definitely seeing that become
more normalized now and I think we'll
see that even go further in the future
uh and that that's that's a steep slope
for sure I think that if you can manage
the time needed for
handling reports and like pring and
stuff like the value add is through the
roof for B yeah if you
get if you find a way to get good people
to have a look at it yeah but but I want
to say also like now I say something
good about platforms now all right all
right all right yeah one change that has
been extremely negative I think is that
platforms like I've never purchased
found the program but I assume that the
sales on the platforms say like okay
this is the standard program and this is
how much uh medium is this is how much
highest this is much briest and that's
freaking [__] yeah like why are they
telling clients like maybe million or
like billion dollar clients billion yeah
it's okay it's okay to pay $1,500 for a
critical no that's ridiculous you can be
there's some like Cop Out argument there
we like oh but it it starts at $1,500
but in reality like most of them just
pay the number that is there so the fact
that multiplatform suggest that to
customers it's really annoys me and it
has not me since they started doing that
yeah I
think standard amounts for
per severity doesn't make sense
for most PR bugs
especially like what what we were
talking about you know with the company
size as well you know these are billion
dooll companies sometimes you know and
and they're paying $1,500 for crit it's
ridiculous um so definitely would like
to see a little bit more of a push from
there and I think from the researcher
side as well I thought about because
yeah I should write this down because
you know critical thinking has a
position where we can we can talk with
um uh the people about things and try to
influence change and try to you know
guide the culture in a specific
Direction and I think it would be
interesting to have some standards some
like Bug Hunter standards essentially
right and say like okay listen if you
are if you've ever found an
rce you know or if you've ever you know
you know reached some certain standard
when you're in training it's whatever
you know but when when you feel like
you're actually serious about this and
you're like okay I'm a capable enough of
a bug Hunter where I'm going to start
holding some you know dignity or
whatever then these are our standards
for bounties I don't look at programs
with a medium above less than a thousand
I don't look at programs with crits less
than 10K you know or something like that
right that's kind of where my standard
kind of sits right now and I would like
to kind of you know get a get and this
is sort of a unish thing of sorts but
like get some of the top hunters and say
okay this is where this is a summary of
where our positions lie and I want to
make sure that you all you know in the
in the other side of the bounty World
understand that so that could be an
interesting thing what are your thoughts
on that and I also want to hear your
personal standards for where your you
know low medium high crit should lie if
you're going to look at a
program well the thing is I understand
some like counter arguments or like if I
play that with
Advocate like
a 10 TH or or like a
$50,000 budget is still $50,000 even if
the whole company's revenue is two
billion yeah that's true so that's like
one thing that I that I can kind of
understand and the second thing is
like it needs to beex dependent because
if it's like a nonprofit like you say or
some small business
then
like then that could make sense H but uh
I think
that I think that they should make a
best effort to to put
out what they feel like the low medium
maybe
High could be worth to them and I think
that the critical should always
be will decide on the
spot and
not defining a minimum
yeah and especially not defining a
maximum that's that's tricky man I H
that's a hot take dude I don't know that
I would hack on a program that says
we'll defi we'll decide the critical
unless they had sort of a track record
of
saying okay we've paid criticals 20
grand 30 grand 40 grand 50 you know like
that sort of thing because if they say
like it's a critical and we're going to
give you you know three and then that
would feel real
bad yeah but like if you don't trust the
program then how can you take those
numbers seriously anyway and also it's
like context dependence within the
program too you know because it's like
oh I got a shell here okay it's a test
box has no data nothing of value
here but yes technically if you put the
cfss in it is a crit and then it's like
bad to the other way too yeah and I I
only think that stand standard amounts
Mak sense
for bugs that will have the same or the
same is impact so an xss it can be the
case like okay an xss under blood comb
will always have is this impact so okay
we can put put a standard on it doesn't
matter if it's this subdomain or this
subdomain or this API or this parameter
it's same but for crit it's
like almost
always different yeah how would you this
if you were on the other side of the
table how would
you decide how much a crit is worth to
your
organization I know that that's a tricky
question we like to we like to ask the
tricky questions here on the CTV podcast
I should giving you a a heads up I've
been asking you to prophesy about the
bug Bounty you know industry I've been
asking you putting yourself in other
people's shoes you know so I know I know
this isn't the easiest thing but yeah
give me your thoughts one thing you
could do is like it depends if you're
just starting out and have no data at
all then you can't really do this but
one thing you can do is
like based on the previous year whatever
like this is how many
criticals we expect to get and given
that the budget is this we can have a
crit budget within that budget so like
10% of that or
something um but you can also try to
evaluate like what the cost of an if of
an attacker exploiting it would be too
you know in terms of like if you have
slas or if you
have like GPR finds yeah or
some some other stuff but that's like
yeah there are some hard cost you can
calculate pretty good at
pgpr but when it comes to Alternative
costs it's so difficult that's like okay
what what about brand damage mhm what's
what's that worth so much money
dude yeah given how little companies
seem to be affected when they get H I
guess not much but well you know it's
common though you know that that's the
problem is
like it's
been I guess normalized of sorts and the
average person isn't saying like Okay
well clearly I I think also so there
could be a problem with um cyber
security reporting representation so you
know we can hear okay you know Facebook
got hacked or whatever and and someone
and it could be like you know some
freaking Matias and fron [__] where you
like you know reverse this thing and
it's like crazy rce that like the best
people in the world could have never
find except for you guys you know and
and they got hacked that way which is in
my opinion pretty much unavoidable right
or it could be there's a numeric idor on
the homepage that allows you that leaks
P password hashes you know like you know
and and the difference to the
average you know cyber
security news listener is nothing and
and the and so I I wonder if there's a
niche sort of reporting market for
something like that that would actually
tell people like hey this
is essentially negligent
right the company didn't do what they
were supposed to do or this is like
pretty much unavoidable because of how
security
works yeah and like here's the
kicker most of the time it's going to be
ship that isn't even in school in bug b
yeah some some person got fished some
person reused the
password that's true well yeah man it's
it's a scary it's a scary a Scary World
out there for this sort of thing Man it
really is um
and there's so many one of the things
that I love about bug Bounty is it's so
tangible you you get what you pay for
with bug Bounty you know like you're
never paying a report where you're not
making a change which is great and so
unlike anything else in the security
industry that's like you know pay us 15K
a month to run this tool you know or or
whatever and who knows what it actually
does or like you know we tell you that
this is the results or whatever right um
but bug Bounty is exactly what you pay
for so I think a bug bug Bounty program
is the best way to sh up your technical
environment but there needs to be some
serious investment made into securing up
your your personal environment as well
you know your your human environment and
that's what I you know I like that
people are doing with the the whole um
keys that you put into your computer I
can't remember the name of them right
now yeah yeah and and you know you
you've got that and it like validates
the website that you're on so you can't
get like evil proxied you know evil Gen
X you know that sort of thing too so I
think there's there's definitely a big a
big area there and I think programs that
you know people that have bug Bounty
programs should absolutely have already
implemented that in their organization
because we all know the easiest way into
an organization is to fish someone um so
no no for sure like I wouldn't recommend
to anyone like take the entire security
budget and put it on like bu yeah that's
that's very different um Maas this has
gone a little bit long already and we
haven't even got into some of the good
stuff do you do you have a hard end or
you are you free for a little
bit no no no we can do it okay I'm just
more nervous like for the listeners and
stuff I don't want to take up people's
no dude dude you know the last response
we got to the fron episode was like this
is amazing two and a half hours of you
know ramblings this is amazing so um oh
you know okay let me say that okay just
put it on like one point 25 speed
exactly right you know that's I listen
to all of my podcasts on two or 2.3
speed and you know when I go back to
normal speed I'm like why does this
person's voice sound so weird you know
like it's like this is where do Smurf go
yeah exactly exactly um all right man so
I
think all right well we've gone down the
whole path of all almost all of the
stuff that I wanted to cover from the
non-technical side but I will ask you
one more thing okay and Joel is here
today Joel has got a new cat so he is uh
dealing with some baby kitten craziness
this morning um and I wanted to make fun
of Joel a little bit I've even got a
note to myself in the document make fun
of Joel here um on the topic of nerd
snip ability now Joel is a great partner
for me in uh in hacking and in the Pod
for so many reasons but one of the
primary reasons that I love him is he is
nerd snip as heck you can tell you can
say like hey Joel I just just really
don't understand this thing like what
what does this mean Joel and then he has
like a obsessive like oh let me I'm
going to figure that out right now you
know sort of response to that it's this
great concept of nerd snip ability and
you mentioned
that you got nerd sniped by a tweet that
I did a while back on um on xss stuff
and I'm wondering do you consider
yourself a particularly nerd snip person
and do you think that is a weakness or a
superpower in your own sort of bug
Bounty Journey but also I guess
knowledge journey in in
security I think yes I am and I also
think it's a positive yeah but the thing
is like nerd snip ability doesn't
always only applied to good stuff like
learning it it security stuff like I
have the same thing
with like I got nerd sniped into World
of Warcraft World of Warcraft yeah yeah
I need to stay away from nonproductive
stuff that can get too interesting yeah
so that's that's that's good to hear you
know I I think I think at the end of the
day it is a net positive because you do
get that
hyperfocus um but I also know that there
are a lot of struggles with that come
with that too um yeah yeah know I uh
it's strange like when I it's same when
I'm hacking I I
love understanding how things work it's
it's awesome to go
from what the hell is this Black Box
until I I understand what it does and I
know I know exactly why you wrote the
code like this and I would do it too if
I didn't think about this and that's why
there surv here yeah but but the way
there is is sometimes like frustrating
and it's yeah no it's strange like
sometimes like if my girlfriend's home
or if I'm sitting somewhere I I keep
like excusing myself because I'm like
swearing and like damn
it I just copy and paste it like why did
you s that extra space like like I'm
really like do you talk to yourself out
loud yeah oh yeah yeah so I'm always
like oh no I'm not angry I just it's
just this thing it needs to I need to
bend it to my will dude yeah and that
that's such a great way of saying it too
bending it to your will and I think that
is so much what happens with bug Bounty
and I think that's another way to
classify researchers is there there are
researchers who will bend the
application to their will and there are
researchers that will look at the
application and find problems that exist
in
it just you know authentically by
looking at the application right you
know it's not like I've got a goal and
I'm going to make that goal happen it's
it's I'm going to find the problems with
this application based off of threat
assessment both of those researchers are
incredibly needed and high value right
but
lately I've been doing the bend bend it
to your will thing like I went into a
live hacking event um this is London
actually and I said okay I'm doing
something a little bit different this
event I'm gonna pick one thing that I
want to have happen and I'm gonna make
it happen and I I sat down and it
actually only took like three three or
five days out of the two we you know
prep period right um and I I made it
happen and it's just like ah I love this
you know like it's just so it warms the
heart right um so when you're when
you're going deep and you're really
bending the application to your will I
think there's a lot of really good
um emotional payoff for that sort of
thing yeah no for sure for sure and I
agree
like one of the bad parts though is
like sometimes I get too much of in a
rush I guess to get to the go so I'm
like
uh not documenting enough my FES name 1
2 3 four yep like my burp tabs
everywhere my Chrome tabs and all and
also like I'll catch myself like okay
I'm gonna go get coffee and then like I
don't walk to the coffee machine I like
Skip and run like yeah what am I doing I
I'm not in a rush that's great dude I
love that or and then you you you know
you run to the coffee machine you pour
the coffee you know you get back as fast
as you can without spilling it you set
it on the desk don't even drink it get
back to the thing right you know like
and it's it's freezing cold by the time
you take the first sip um so no I
totally get that and it's so funny man
you know one 123. txt a.txt I think it
was Cosman the first guy that said that
on the Pod but it's really funny how so
many of us are having that you know be a
problem and this is something that I'm
actually really looking forward to in
the AI space is like can I have an AI
assistant that
will just organize stuff for me right
like how helpful would it be if you know
you were in kaido and you like send a
you know a request to repeater or
something like that and it like smart
named it for you or something like that
right by looking at the request and or
or like you know you you create a.txt
and it and it says okay a.txt and then
in parentheses it says notes on XYZ
Target right you know like that sort of
thing would be so helpful um and so
that's something I'm really looking
forward to in the AI space I think
that'll be I think that'll be here
before long with the rate at which
people are going after AI startups right
now um yeah I can I give another yeah d
d I love that yes okay
so one recommendation I have when when
it comes to documentation and knowing
what the hell you did
is um I should PR this okay just
if you have some startup script or when
you're opening burp or your to love
Choice kto
yes I recommend sending everything
through there and then doing the
filtering in the tool itself instead of
having like filters in the uh in like
your poxy extension Etc because then you
you have everything nothing can just
vanish and go missing and yes it will
require like more RAM and re
but it has helped me so many times um by
doing that and also the first thing I
also do in the in my startup script is I
SSH into one of my boxes but you can
also send a request through ver maybe
someone has talked about this already
yes so you know like this is what my IP
was my external IP was at the time yeah
in case you need it for later dude
that's great and and you you mentioned
that in the in the talk and I did find
the talk by the way it's how to
differentiate yourself as a bug Bounty
Hunter um and I will link that in the
description uh but you mentioned that in
there as well saying like never ever
ever let go of your data just just you
know storage is cheap go to the store
get a 8 terabyte you know external hard
drive drop those burp files onto it you
know uh after you're done and then
someday when you're like oh I've got
this zero day you know that affects
everything that has the parameter you
know xyz123 you just go to that that
whole folder you set up like a rip grip
and you just say all right give me
everything that has xyz123 in it and now
you've got years of data sort of piling
up there um it's awesome I definitely do
that I've got an external hard drive
right in front of me that has over 100
gigabytes probably probably over 500
gigabytes of of burp and and kaido files
actually I don't know that I have all my
kaido stuff on it yet because kaido just
kaido so offic with it um that I can G
through which is really
handy that's actually something I I'm
curious about too like do you have any
kaido projects which are really big
because I feel like around the 500,000
request Mark burp is like really
struggling even opening and yeah let me
look at this right now I have a kaido
project it's this one right here that is
22 gigabytes um and it's the same thing
that is the is let me tell you how many
requests are on it um yeah just roughly
yeah
uh
350,000
requests in the actual project and then
I probably
got I've got over 200 probably close to
300 repeater tabs and then like 20
automate sessions which is the
equivalent of of intruder right and the
thing still works just like like you
know it did whenever I booted up kaido
you know for the first time with the
exception of obviously searches are
going to take a little bit longer and
who knows maybe they'll have optimized
that with um you know the next search
patch or whatever but yeah I hope they
did build something to make it
searchable like in memory I think that's
one of the differences if I'm not
mistaken with logger Plus+ versus to
normal search plus we like to load
everything into RAM oh my God time
search yeah that's not that's not great
that that is real bad yeah and I also
just want to shout out the fact that
when you asked me that it took me less
than 10 seconds to switch into that
project and you know get in from the
project that I had open and check the
request count which is just so beautiful
and my my uh my workspaces in kaido are
so much cleaner because you can
literally it's like one click to change
projects no lag time so really love that
um Okay so technical [__] yeah technical
[__] yes I'm sorry we've been waiting
you know it's an hour and a half in I
might actually add a little disclaimer
at the beginning of this episode um you
know that a lot of the uh technical [__]
will be uh you know at the you know 1
hour 30 Mark or whatever uh yeah it's
funny the tips you yeah all the tips are
great too so you know those those are
technical as well um yeah dude you can't
you can't leak my my uh super secret
titles for the document that we have on
this side of the of the Pod I send him
this document and there's two categories
it's like technical [__] and personal
[__] and uh we spent a little bit little
bit long in the personal [__] section I
should have just introduced you and then
went right into the technical [__] but
here we are and we got some great tips
along the way so I'm I'm happy with it
um so a part of my research for the
technical [__] section is um going
through every tweet you've ever ever
tweeted and finding all the interesting
stuff and uh talk getting ready to talk
about that so you put out this Tool
uh hack a planet 10 uh no it's it's hack
the planet in Swedish can you say it
hak
haket I don't know man l s someday
that's great you own that domain the SE
domain and HTML parse in it this is
super awesome so essentially what it
does you go to this this thing here you
submit an HTML document and then it runs
D purify on it it and it puts it through
all of these
um different serers side HTML renderers
and shows you the result um so tell me
why you did this and can you well first
explain you're looking for mutation xss
here
apparently why are you looking for
mutation xss and what is mutation xss
s okay so mutation xss is like if you
take a payload and just give it to the
browser no no alert box will pop
essentially but if you put it through
some Brer first like even one that's
inside of the browser itself which is M
say like right inner
HTML uh setting or uh like the D parser
um Etc and then it will essentially try
to fix
errors in the markup and while inserting
those fixes it
actually turns it into like SS let's say
so so if I'm understanding correctly the
browser or the the sort of I guess Dom
rendering engine whatever it is it could
be a serers side HTML parser could be a
browser could be you know some other mod
modification within the browser when
you give it some HT HL document that is
not spec compliant typically right you
know it it it will look at this thing
and say okay can't render this because
it's not spec compliant let me see what
I can do to fix it and when it does that
it will inadvertently cause excess is
that right yeah that's exactly right
it's a bug in the I'll fix your bad
markup love that thank you for your help
uh browsers and Dom renders all around
we we love that you we can rely on you
for this sort of thing so so what was
the motivation for this tool man what
did you why did you build this and what
kind of stuff have you been finding with
it well the motivation was it actually
had nothing to do with
xss
but yeah well it was
like it was like a XML bug but I know
they accepted you it was weird because
you could send HTML to it instead of XML
and I was like hm I wonder what parser
they're using because they were such
certain tags they wouldn't allow me to
use and I needed them to explo stuff
yeah and I had this idea like I wonder
if I can hide the tags from them somehow
but when it forwards it it will actually
be unhidden
because some other bser where it
actually ends up after that treats it in
a different way so I was like okay how
surely there's some tool you can just
spin up all of these things and see like
how does each par par it and it's like
nope and an standard moment in all life
oh man someone should build this I'm
that someone I guess I'm
someone so that's great man so you you
went and you built it you took how many
geez I mean you press Parson here and it
just keeps on going so you've got so
many 16 parsers wow dude how much of a
pain in the butt was that to uh to do I
mean the biggest problem was choosing
whether I
should Implement like a whole web stack
for it or if I should make like a hack
which I ended up doing
like do I need to make have like a web
server and a whole MBC framework just to
call this parsing function and see what
it
does U but instead do it built it with
Apache and CGI actually and then it will
just run
like live version of it wow very cool
man yeah so that's I took the shs about
this actually which way to do it in in a
practical way because I'm like it's
going to take a long time if I'm going
to have to build an actual application
yeah is dude oh I see you open sourced
it too yeah yeah yeah so that's what I
did and uh oh it's got Docker it's got
dude I did not see this when I did the
research this this uh no each each one
of them is a own Docker container no
dude and then so okay so you've got it
in a Docker container and then you can
literally just do Echo your your your
Dom pipe it into Docker exec and then
give it the name of the parcel you want
and it'll just do
it yeah that's dude this is so you can
like f it through that if you like too
or you can use the
the beautiful web interface this is
really well architected dude I'm really
impressed nice nice work with this do
you have any um so did you did you pop
the XML thing or no I did I did and uh
like because I I managed
to uh
hide tags with it because it pared the
um HTML comments incorrectly it didn't
recognize dash dash
exclamation greater than as an end of a
comment ah you can also so like
okay if you if you view sour on
like
in that's like a I have put in like a
combination of those things that I found
for different Parcels that we like hide
the content of the document oh up up at
the top there is that no what do you
like um on just the homepage of
of. if you take for example just
standard
uh beautiful soup and H water and and
you try to scrape my site and like take
the links you cannot do it no way
really and it's same with like
flop a couple hours but um so yeah that
was like the second like interesting
challenge I thought of when building
that just like hm I wonder if we can
hide
[Music]
from from scraper
like what implementations can't can't be
the good old Rex
though that's true that's true yeah no
that's really cool though I love that
you built that in that's like some
serious hacker hacker [__] right there
when you like make your own you
implement this on your own website just
for the kicks yeah so that they can't
you know pull your LinkedIn and your
Twitter from aen br. that's high value
high value links you've got there only
for human eyes um yeah I know no so I
did find some stuff and I have been
thinking about implementing like the
same with XML forers to too because
that's something that I that I
think could have specific bugs too like
someone wants a research
area pick a bunch of different
standardized xmal parsers see how they
treat like external book types or other
type
of xxc issues and play around with it
because there was someone in in
The Thinking podcast disc actually I
don't think they meant what I thought
they meant but they gave me an idea that
like okay maybe there's a part that
doesn't require the do declaration to be
at the start of the document and oh I I
saw that conversation that looked
interesting but but that would make
xxc I can type of XC I guess which would
be like external doct type injection so
when when you're injecting into the body
of the instead yeah controlling whole
things so I actually have a a piece of
research that I want to say I don't
remember whether I actually put it into
the samle episode for for critical
thinking but there is a Chrome browser
exploit that was a couple weeks ago not
the one that that dropped in the
critical thinking research uh xx1
recently um where they were using xslt
transforms yeah to do some crazy stuff
with the placement of that entity you
know the doc type tag um and so there
essentially it was like it was using the
parser to stick it up at the top and on
one on the first parser it would it
would not have it at the top and on the
next one it would and then trigger the
xxe
so the other cool thing you can do with
that is the xslt transforms which I am
really excited to dive into deep more I
hope I hope some of the listeners go and
do this research because I I'm super
swamped with stuff right now but I would
love to see any research research on
xslt maybe I can nerd snipe you on it
dude the transforms are so cool have did
have you have you like learned it all
about xslt transforms yeah yeah I found
ex self bug like one and a half week ago
oh my gosh of course you have all right
whatever whatever Matias all right but
that mean it was one and a half a week
ago so it means I forgot everything yeah
your your context window is
gone no that's great man so all right
well then so you've actually done some
more Hands-On stuff with it than I have
because I've just done mostly reading
and ideating on it um what is your yeah
share sh share a little bit about that
would
you I can share about that but I it was
really interesting point that you
brought up with this XLT because xslt is
basically meant to like transform the
incoming XML document to something else
yeah
so it's prear transform it you could
transform it into something that now has
an xsc in it that's yeah I I guess
that's what you meant but have to
revisit it because it's awesome that's
great man I could see you he's for those
of you that are are listening not
watching on YouTube there's like this
far off look in his eyes that is the the
the mark of of a a bug forming I can see
it that's great man I love that um yeah
there's also a lot of stuff or there are
different couple of different EXT
libraries but you can do like file
system stuff yeah to and get like
environment variables and stuff so you
can even do more stuff than with just
normal 16 yeah 100% And so yeah I'd like
to normally before people come in the
podcast I message them and I say hey you
know check out this document you know
that's thing right and then I also tell
them hey bring a bug or two so that we
can talk about it on the Pod and I
totally forgot to do that for you for
this episode so I'm sorry about that we
can talk about that one yeah can you can
you give us some info on that that'd be
great so that one was you could
upload an XML okay through a bunch of
different Hoops you have to jump through
but it ended with like you could provide
an XML and then in another place you
could provide an
xslt
document
and the funnyest thing is the xslt
document is also specified as XML right
and and that that one was vulnerable to
xxc but I didn't find it because I tried
it in the original document that was not
vulnerable so then I like okay xslt I'm
going to learn it xslt specific parts
and then like after I played with it and
talk to France about it he like but this
is 6C freaking FR dude shut up shut up
like get out of here who invited you to
this
anyway but in another way so
one Noel trick that I learned with that
was that I forget exactly what the
operation was called but there's like a
couple of ways you can read files and
you can read Json files with one
operation I can try and write it later
we can we can link to this documentation
write or you sorry you can read it's
documents but you can also read raw
files yeah but the problem
is oh this is connecting to the next
part actually of this secret document uh
you could
also in the parer you weren't allowed to
read read the no byes into the the ah
resulting document like oh damn can't
read like Pro self Environ yeah like
separated windows uh but what you could
do is specify the encoding of the file
so what you could do is you could tell
it treat it
as like youf 16 for example and it would
spit out like a bunch of Chinese
characters and then you could like
transform that
back and I knew that it was a Java
application so I could just use H worker
and then know that it's like Java versus
jav so I actually expected like the
environment via like reading the file as
you 16 and then turn it back dude that
is you've been doing so much crazy Char
set stuff lately man that's that's
really cool you bypass that with that
though that's that's an amazing idea I
like I like I
suppose type confusion bugs yeah like
it's a broad area they they are my one
of my favorites and coding is like I I'm
still not entirely sure I there's a blog
post actually I I can link to it too
it's like really old like 2007 or
something sure and it's called something
like everything you need to know about
encodings and short sets as a developer
okay I need that okay so yeah yeah and
it starts from the beginning like the
beginning there was a and we did that
there was the S and then like the high
bites was not used for anything and then
so
people started implementing whatever
they wanted over like zx80 and uh that
wasn't really standardized but then IBM
was like okay we take all of them and we
give the each a code page number so now
when you see like a short sets it's like
cp12 34 yeah that's that's the code page
wow dude that's that's cool man I would
love to read that document I think that
I think a lot of our listeners would
love to read that too so I'll um we'll
I'll follow up with you after that and
try to try to get that in the
description yeah
um encoding box is
really really really interesting too and
also things
like injecting like bite order Mark to
to
confuse injecting
what bite order Mark oh bite order Mark
tells yeah so you can use it in likef 16
for example or like is this the like
ening flip it around thing like the left
to right
override yeah exactly it's it's like if
it's little Eng or big engan like should
the top bite come first or second oh oh
yeah yeah yeah so you're talking about
like um like uh UTF 16 Le UTF 16 be is
that what you're talking about exactly
exactly so if you say UTF 16 right then
it's ambiguous but you can start the the
document or the string of strings yeah
with with like it is bite order which
like f FF I think for one of them and
and then then it's like aha you're
telling it to what coding is okay so
hold on wait a second so you can
actually put that in the
data yeah
what
B
order Mark dang dude I need a bigger
notepad for this episode um bite order
Mark and so you can put that in the data
and it will Define how the rest of that
data string is readed
it should have to start with it but I
wouldn't be surprised if some people or
some interpreters of far could have it
in the
middle holy crap that's amazing that is
that is super I'm just kind of yeah now
now I've got the thing in my you know
I'm looking off into the into the
distance and and ideating on on what
what could become of that that's that's
really really interesting dude I'm
definitely going to have to look into
that after this um
yeah thanks so much for sharing that I'm
sure that'll result in a bunch of in a
bunch of bugs um yeah there's also some
encodings that have special I don't
think it's called B order marks but it's
like a special sequence of characters
that like transform it so like in the
middle of the document you can have bite
blah and blah and then it TS it to like
okay now it's this other way of
interpreting it and it ends with
something
else no way there is encoding which is
like okay now it's FY everything is fine
it's like no now it is not now it's this
other thing dude that is so interesting
so if you could get them to parse it
with that Char set then you could really
use that to bypass and security controls
because you know
whatever parser will be looking at it
and being like okay you know this is
just meaningless text and then when the
actual end you know program runs it it's
something completely different because
it's it's actually parsing the Char set
differently yeah yeah exactly so if they
have like a spren complaints for example
then it could
be different dude this has got be they
do this was a topic too in the Discord I
saw like normalization they can like
transform it into yeah some some other
well this is this is very and you know
of course my mind goes directly to web
servers and reverse proxies and wafts
and this is actually pretty much exactly
what Sam BB and I were talking about and
I I don't know if you saw it in the
document but I I did a talk on this at
Defcon um on how you can Define host
headers for some uh for some HTTP
servers and you can Define them in
different encodings right so literally
our expit for this bug was host and this
is a host header host colon equals
question mark ISO 8859-1 question mark q
and then a bunch of hex data and that
actually got converted into into our
exploit on on the the back end of that
um server that we were talking to it
bypassed the engine x uh configuration
that had some limits on the host header
characters being used and allowed us to
inject right into the engine X config
file on the back end because of the way
that we could smuggle characters like a
space and stuff like that into the host
header um and so now I'm thinking like
man there's got to be even more
possibilities of this sort of thing with
stuff that that can change
mid you know mid uh mid flow and change
into something else because maybe the
engine X proxy on the front end reads
decodes the character set but the one on
the back end doesn't and it doesn't
normalize it and then it just treats it
like normal text and then you can pop
xss or you can you know bypass any sort
of filtering there's in
place yeah but like you also need
to you when you're talking about excess
you need either you need service side
normalization for it to transform
because when you're sending like you're
using you that's 16 for example what
what you're actually sending is just two
bites and and if you want like a less
than characters those two bites will be
no bite and 3C so if it filters 3C in
like an 8bit as encoding it it would go
like okay is this a 3C is this a 3C no
sure say yes and so you need need
normalization or you need some kind of
encoding supported in the client that
were like 03 C or
033 f means less than I'm wondering if
there's other there's got to be other
encodings besides you know UTF 8 utf16
that put those at different code points
right in browsers no well you know and I
linked actually funny you mentioned that
Matias because I did my homework for
this episode and if you click the first
the first link under the character sets
um heading in the secret document I have
a a link directly to the chromium source
code and all of the different um uh
character encodings that we you know
that can be used in here and I see one
of them you know is this ISO 8859-1 that
I'm famili more familiar with from the
the Defcon talk and so I'm wondering if
there's different ways you know or any
of these different encodings put a
different
put the you know less than sign or
greater than sign or whatever at a
different code point so that if if if it
it bypasses the front end and says okay
you know the front end says this is uh
you know a question mark But the back
end says okay I'm actually not reading
this as as you know Windows D1 you know
1252 and actually I'm I'm interpreting
this as utf8 or interpreting this as
aski and then you know you get the
output as an actual script tag does that
does that make sense or am I thinking
about this
incorrectly I mean it's a good idea but
the iso
8859 yeah it's different it's no it is
es based no no I know I know it's not
what we're it it doesn't meet the
standards of what we're we're looking at
yeah but but is there is something like
that yes unfortunately I don't think
that there
is
U any nonas supported Char sets for like
HTML and dangerous content
so the the over they used to be they
used to be yeah especially like Internet
Explorer had some special cases and like
all of them at some points for the uf7
which is just like seven seven bit so
asky aski would be so the base for all
these is what you're saying so the first
256 characters of every single one that
3C is always going to be the the angle
bracket for for ex yeah es is the all
the you need and pation for the English
language so it starts at serx 20 and
stopped at
at seven like small letter c yeah at
least that's how I learned in my room
yeah yeah and and oh actually speaking
of I was going to say in the start but
one of the best
ways
um to learn I believe is to be wrong
yeah so if I say something that is wrong
please tell me yeah and also like
uh trust but verify when it comes to
people teaching you that's like a super
free way to
learn heck yeah dude I love this and I
also love that you're in the ctbb
Discord I appreciate that by the way you
know I people are asking questions in
there all the time about stuff like you
know XML and about um you know uh
character sets or some of these more
advanced topics right and you're in
there like responding to questions and
like getting nerd sniped by the by the
content which I really I I definitely
appreciate and and I totally agree man
once
again Matias I think you'd like
podcasting man because uh I'm not not
not trying to you know drum drum me up
some uh bug Bounty competition uh bug
Bounty podcast competition but you know
you you're out there every week you're
talking for an hour and a half you know
and you're and you're making mistakes
and people are messaging you saying hey
you messed this up and then you just get
free correction you know yeah and if
you're not taking yourself too seriously
you know um then it's great and you and
you you learn so much so yeah we might
have to uh you know get the Matias show
started or or we might have to make you
get get you on here on a regular basis
maybe you'll be the um uh Joel is having
some cat problems uh you know sub host
in in the future um but yeah definitely
actually it reminds me of this uh what
there's some late night show I think
it's Conan or some one of them where
they have like special episodes where
like the viewers can come on and like H
you you were wrong about this because
this like that's an idea oh just like a
roast episode oh my gosh like people can
like point out like
actually dude that's a great idea I
gotta if you could stach that I got a no
no no no 100% I've got a um
I'm going to write that down I'm going
to try to make a uh a channel in the in
the in the uh Discord in the CTV podcast
Discord of like Corrections you know
stuff Justin said that was wrong and
it's G to make me feel so bad but I'm
gonna learn so much that's a great idea
dude um but yeah I would be really
interested to see you know especially
with some of these uh character sets
that are oriented specifically towards
other languages you know like the
Japanese um the iso uh 2022 p uh
character set or some of these other
stuff what is actually you know if
they're all asky compliant or whether
there's ways to represent different code
points you know in different ways that
are outside of asky definitions and
still get an asy result back um that
would be that would be really
interesting and then also but of course
you've got the the sort of normalization
piece which is often in place you know
I've got the Japanese keyboard set up on
my computer uh and and I always just
switch it over to to Japanese and drop
in the uh you know J the full width um
less than and greater than um you know
for the xss stuff and I've definitely
had that pop quite a few times yeah well
that can actually be a an easy way to
bypass WS too yeah if the server side
supports uf7 but the wa doesn't just
send it that's I want to say was it
won't see it
was it
suou
uh W bypass I think that's that's an
unrated dude yeah yeah 100% I I'd love
to have him on the on the on the podcast
sometime I believe yeah I'll link it in
the in the description as well for those
of you guys that are listening but suou
um uh dalili sorry Ur is his is his
handle I don't really know how to
pronounce last names sometimes or first
names in that regard but we'll link it
in the description below has an article
from 2018 on using character sets to
bypass waffs and this is
incredibly um incredibly applicable and
often used to bypass waffs and also saw
a tweet going around the other day I'm
not sure if you saw this from um jsh I
think is his name I don't know how to I
don't have it in front of me so I'm not
sure but he's been dropping a bunch of
cool tips lately and we talked about a
couple of them on the Pod and one of the
ones he did was a WAFF bypass that just
says uh content en coding as the header
as the HTTP header and then it the
content is just wa bypass so essentially
if there's any content encoding header
the W's like ah you know what actually I
don't know how to deal with that [__]
I'm just going to pass it through and
hope you figure it out uh and I just
thought that was hilarious like what
kind of BS waffs people are
using yeah it's I they have basically
never been effictive except for maybe
specific automated effects yeah yeah
yeah for for sure I think they ought to
look at the um the wa should look at or
maybe they shouldn't look at but uh the
port swiger cheat sheets on like
impossible xss scenarios like you know
if you can just block less you know left
than bra or less than bracket A through
Z then you're screwed right there's no
way you can really get around that um as
far as HTML context injection goes um
because that's just a part of the spec
you know it has to be an Alpha character
you know coming right after it so it's a
bummer hopefully someone will crack that
one someday because if they do there's
going to be a lot of excesses popping
left and right um all right man let's
see we are at two hours
already
I let's let's skip over some of this and
talk
about your favorite go-to
vulnerabilities and stuff that you find
yourself finding often you know if you
had to profile so a while ago let me add
some context to this question while you
think about that um a while ago You
released this uh this dashboard with
fron I believe Bounty Dash and you know
You' pull in before the the programs
were doing this sort of thing it pull in
all your reports and like categorize
them and give you earnings you know per
certain period of time and you know what
kind of severity vones there were and
that sort of thing and vulnerability
classes I think were included as well um
if you were to profile
Matias as a as a as a BG Bounty Hunter
what kind of stuff would be your bread
and butter what would be your go-to
vulnerabilities that you often
find I often look
for high or CR level stuff so it's
always like context dependent depending
on the organization I almost always
start with trying to understand
what does the organization have value
protecting yeah so that I can then
follow up with
okay what are they protecting it with
and how is it supposed to work okay it's
authentication authorization okay how is
that supposed to be implemented
yesterday you can have in the back of
your head like okay these are the things
that they probably care
about um but the specific
bugs like I found a I find a bunch of
bus on the way like excesses that just
are
obvious so you don't ignore those lower
medium impact vones in search of the
higher crits but you no no no like why
why why use Matias in this field if I
can just like use a bunch of quotes and
some stuff yeah yeah yeah it takes me
the same amount of time
yep but yeah I don't know I like type
confusion and I like different kinds of
injections and I also like
like this reverse proxy type of bugs too
reverse proxy types of bugs let's let's
talk a little bit about that how do you
are you doing vhost level fuzzing for
that is that the sort of thing you're
talking about or are you talking about
secondary context path reversals or yeah
yeah exactly secondary context
stuff yeah one of the tips we've dropped
before on the Pod for that sort of thing
is you know traversing all the way back
pass the document route and then cutting
off everything after will result in a
400 getting dropped on the status code
so with that you can determine the
document route on on the backend server
that you're that you're traversing with
do you have any other cool tips or
tricks you can drop on secondary context
bugs identifying them and uh exploiting
them or is it just mostly a fuzz game
because that that that is part of it I
know for sure I mean request smuggling
is the say same like that's also a thing
where you can get like the different
applications in the chain to trade the
request
differently what else do you do you
actively exploit request smuggling in
these sort of
scenarios on a let's say you know
multiple times a year basis you think I
don't automatically like scan for it or
anything but I will look at it if
I sporadic I guess I don't know if I
feel like it I guess bad answer but
that's just intuition I suppose but also
like one one actual tip
is it's kind of fussy in the standard
whether uh hashtag or fragment character
is allowed in a path or not yeah yeah so
a lot of times what I see is that like
the first load balance or whatever it's
like okay that's just a part of the path
but then when it forward it to the back
end the path is uh kind
so that's like another way if you can't
if you need a way to trunk it the rest
of the path because maybe there's some
reverse proxy match so you need to have
the surfix yeah so that's like a good
tip yeah using that using the um the
query parameter you know the question
mark as well we'll get you that
sometimes for sure and that truncation
is so helpful man one of the things I've
struggled with though let's see if
you've got any thoughts on this I I
don't know if you you've had this one
and I'm not sure there's a great
solution to it but is this concept of
like okay I'm injecting in the middle of
a secondary context you know situation
right so I've got some text before and
I've got some text after right um the
text before you can Brute Force by you
know path traversing deleting it and
then brute forcing and if it completes
the request the way that you would
anticipate that it should be completed
then you've identified the correct path
there right um but on the right side how
can we without some sort of verbos error
I struggle to enumerate what is on the
right side of our injection
Point some kind of verb yeah are you are
you tracking with me or or no yeah okay
we're still talking about like the path
part yeah like the first first line of
the reest yeah yeah yeah well one thing
you could do is
like try to make it extremely long and
then you can see maybe see like
path and then it just ends that
interesting that's one way to do it
another way you could do it is plus size
inflation yeah interesting oh yeah and
then it would drop back a what is it a
44 like uh 414 status code I believe
which is like uh yeah URI too long
response status code right so and then
you could use that to prot like
potentially determine
if you if you know the full path to the
left and you don't know the path to the
right you could at least get a character
count at least probably on the yeah that
how much is there by determining by
inflating the size and then determining
where you get the 414 status
code yes huh that's not what I meant but
that's a good
idea well that's what happens when we
get on these pods we kind of ideate and
bounce off bounce off of each other
that's good though I like
that yeah like the same thing with the
like the query and stuff too like you
can make a question mark and then put
something you think is an invalid
character and it might spit back like
quy names cannot be named blah blah blah
so that's like another yeah try so
so fuzz the path fuzz the query
fuzz fuzz the query parameters
themselves that you might be able to
identify are getting parsed right
because those might throw a weird error
inflate the request yeah okay yeah you
can also like throw a mer and try like
yes a s in it because sometimes there
will be like
what Hail Mary oh Hail Mary no no no
you're good I I didn't hear it you're
good it cut out yeah but like SL static
SL blah goes to some other back
yeah then instead of they might have a
bad rule so you can do like SL staic
example.com and then there would be like
ssrf and and you can look at the fls and
you get interesting and you understand
I'm kind of cheating in your scenario no
no no that that's great because let's
say for example the the back end is like
SL API slash you know blot blah bla.com
or whatever right you you you Traverse
back you do or no SL API and then
whatever path and instead you put you
you can delete the API right part and
then write API again at whatever and
that will interesting that's some that's
something I've always struggled with
because I was like man wouldn't it be
great if we could Traverse all the way
back up and then you know make it a
slash slash right and have it point to a
different domain it doesn't really make
a lot of sense in a lot of scenarios but
in some normalization scenarios I
actually have popped that vulnerability
before which is
insane and I'll actually show you a a
very impactful one I've got after this
episode um uh but yeah no that's another
great way to get around it is if you can
figure out what that mapping might be
you can find some engine X style um
reverse proxy misconfigurations even on
that backend and try to try to use those
to hit different
domains yeah like here's another
like probably should never work but I've
have seen it once at least wow so the
whole
I don't know if it's in Spec but usually
they allow to put Port there I think
it's because you can have a port if
provide a full U instead of like a
relative in get space agent be so a lot
of partes are lant or the web service or
whatever with the port part of
the post and P so one time at least I've
seen you can do like host example.com
col 0 at
hope yeah dude you know that I want to
say who was it um it was James Kettle
HTTP I can't remember the name it's like
like hitting practical HTP like H
injections or something what what is the
name of that research it's like the
untapped attack surface or like ah I
can't remember
HTP no no no no no it's
it's now it's not just practical HTP
host header attacks I don't think which
is the first one that comes up when I
Google it but there's there is um there
was because now he's got all of this
stuff on ah exploding https hidden
attack surface I think is the one that I
was thinking of a report or a um Talk he
did back in I want to say it was 2017 or
maybe before that at uh at Defcon um has
this very similar thing and I know at
the time you know if you were in the
Life hacking event scene which I'm sure
this is where why you thought of this as
well people were
destroying stuff on uh on on Yahoo with
this it was like like they Yahoo must
have paid out hundreds of thousands if
not millions of dollars in bounties from
this specific vulnerability um so
hopefully you've got that fixed now
Yahoo sorry about that if I just uh you
know called out your your your problem
that are still active but if you don't
have it fixed by now 5 years later
you're doing something wrong so I want
to I want to give some motivation
actually yeah based on that so Yahoo
launched the program what 2012 13
yeah 2019 I found an RC on the root main
domain
real so don't give up just because it's
like oh this [__] is so hard and and
whatever in 200
19 19 yeah wow
dude yeah so there you go that's that is
many many years later you know people
people fuss about this sort of thing all
the time like ah you know this program's
been around for three years like I got
this private program invite it's three
years old what was
me many years later s years later just
go to any any company or do your job or
something that has like the stuff as
open source look at chain
SL and scroll back
to whatever and look how many changes
there like of course there will be yeah
I'm gonna send you I'm GNA send you
something after this as well
um there's this there's this host right
now that I'm I'm working on or that I've
been working on and nogi finally
convinced me to give it up I guess um
but there's the version number says that
it has patched this severe vulnerability
that's at that at that specific version
right if you see the version number in
the HTTP response it says you know
version whatever and it the
vulnerability is patched at that at that
version but if you go into the GitHub
history and you click the patch right
before that before they fix the
vulnerability the commit right before
that it's a it's a change to the read me
for this and it changes a uppercase H to
a or a a lowercase H to an uppercase H
and I hit that read me file and it's
still a lowercase H which means I know
that they haven't actually patched that
specific vulnerability yet um even
though the version number aligns with
the patched version um and so I've been
trying to build out this exploit I had
to rewrite it because of uh HTP htps
problem and something isn't something
isn't the attack complexity might be too
much in this scenario because it there's
some mitigating factors but I might pass
it to you anyway see if I can nerd snipe
you and get you to pop it cuz a 15K bug
if we could um I'll give it yeah man uh
but you know that sort of thing looking
at the change log looking at the get
commit history for open source software
is super duper yeah oh important hey one
more yeah if they program your your your
targeting has like an
SDK oh my gosh your Auto in your
automation P get updates from the SDK
and then you get a feed of like here
here something changed and then like you
don't think crawling you don't think
scraping they will just tell you here
this changed yeah dude and the SDK is a
very
underestimated attack surface as well
for a lot of companies as well that's
one thing that I didn't look at for
years until freaking
rotak uh the the guy that won Vegas two
years back like just started because his
whole thing is like source code review
he's just like literally a source code
monster and he just you know just he'll
open up a page right this is this is how
you know you're dealing with someone
who's like a savant right like he opens
up a page and then he'll read the
JavaScript from top to bottom like not
not jump around not not trace the
functions he'll read it from top to
bottom and then tell you what's
happening with it and I'm like what like
what is what are you how what are you
doing um and he just destroys any SDK
that he he works on on you know on these
programs because it's open source stuff
and he loves open source stuff so really
amazing to see him work on that really
inspiring for me to go after SDK related
um vums and then I found a bunch after
that which is really exciting um so yeah
definitely definitely a great tip there
as far as attack surface and as far as
Recon goes yeah but also like another
tip I guess is
that modern development or if they have
ank or something of the source it
usually bu with like is it called test
driven development I don't know but it
has a bunch of tests and you and a lot
of times those have like security
related tests because they used to have
the bar yeah so that can be like a
really good tip to like oh if you can
just bypass one of these tests you got a
free
bu wow that's giving you a tip on MAR
yeah they they sort of say okay hey this
is what we've this is how we've designed
it to work you know and then you can
look at at the holes from from that
perspective and you know what not to try
that's that that is helpful man you know
Matias you have probably done one of the
best jobs of of anyone on the podcast
that we've had on of actually giving
actionable
Hands-On advice and tips to people I
have it in my note notes right now I'm
gonna have uh some of the viewers play a
drinking game of how many times matus
says here's a tip during this episode
people are going to be like wasted as
heck after that that's great but it's
like I listen to the podcast too so like
I want
to contribute that's great man I
appreciate that um so we're we're we're
getting to the point where it gets way
too long uh but I do want to I want to
have a conversation real quick about
graphql I think we'll skip Docker
escapes which is the other thing that we
were going to talk about even though
that would be really really interesting
um graphql stuff talk to me about
graphql stuff what kind of stuff Have
You Been popping with that recently and
what kind of stuff finding
interesting so I had this notion of or
idea of graph just being like it's the
same thing to test like a by the way
background I started I just started
learning like more about gra but my
previous idea of it was like it's the
same thing as rest API and if
introspection is on you get the
documentation of the rest data basically
you get a bunch of import arguments and
you can like payloads in them and such
that's for traditional vulnerabilities
but turns out there's a lot Bor of that
because you have a bunch of
the not Fields whatever you call them
not Mel attributes you have a bunch of
what do you whatever semantics you have
a bunch of operations let's say so they
can be three types they can be query
quation or a subscription yeah and the
subscription one's also interesting yeah
I want to pick your brain about that
actually actually but go continue
yeah and there's a bunch of like query
names for example but those names can
return an object that has a subquery in
it and this I didn't know y so it's like
a really fun game of like okay I'm
getting back this H it has a field
contacts and the contact field it
actually has a like user Conta contact
type and that one has a user and ah now
I can get the user
can I map all of these different types
you know how can I follow this sort of
train of of data you know to the actual
data type that I want to get access
to EXA so that that's something I I
didn't
know yeah that's that's freaking amazing
man I I I love embedding subqueries like
that and trying to map it out and and
when it has introspection enabled it's
so much easier because you can put it
through stuff like you know um what is
it graphql
I forget what it's called but you you
can paste this the schema in there I've
got it in my bookmark somewhere um and
it and it will actually create like a a
graphical representation of it and you
can say okay this type's linked to this
type it's leaked to this type leaks to
this type and actually I've like yeah
I've had it before where they'll
actually
link like password reset tokens and like
literal password hashes if you chain it
you know to a point and then you ask for
that specific field uh which is like
nuts to me that they would that they
would just expose their whole database
like that yeah yeah no it's it's a lot
more complex than I thought it would be
so so I'm I'm more familiar with the
query and the mutation thing talk to me
about the last one subscribe is it
subcription yeah subscription
subscriptions are
like how should you call it asynchronous
queries or mutations okay so you create
a subscription and then you have either
a web socket or a multiart mixed request
talking about like excess challenge but
it uses this uh and then you have like
an
open socket and whenever something is
answered or put into that subscription
whatever you asked for you'll get paid
about it wow that's that is
uh that is very very interesting I did
not know that that that it was using
that multi-art thing that you had in
your in your Challen I didn't solve your
heart challenge by the way that was that
I don't think it's like I'm not sure if
it's graph standard but like Apollo
graph yeah one which is like almost like
a yeah no that's a lot and and I yeah we
meant I meant to kind of try to talk
through actually that xss challenge and
kind of got lost in the whole um content
content type uh description but or the
um sorry Char set description or
conversation we had but I'll link it
link it below the write up that you have
uh to this to this xss challenge you did
a great job of actually writing up
something at the end that explains all
of the different techniques that you can
use to to do it and there's one um the
multi-art mix that you mentioned I was
on that trail by the way when I was
trying to exploit it but I just didn't
have the time to get all the way through
it um very very cool piece of
functionality that essentially allows if
I understood it correctly it allows them
to almost sort of keep an O It's almost
like websockets but for HTTP and you can
kind of like
continue to stream data over time that
that have individual content documents
within one long streamed HTP response is
that
right that's exactly right yeah wow what
an interesting piece of uh functionality
there and I I have to imagine that the
the impact of that is substantial in the
context of things like uh HTTP request
smuggling and stuff like that too so
definitely some room for some cool
research there for anybody who is into
request smuggling and sort of server
confusion confusing servers yeah that's
like
if like one way you can do something
with a response injection for example or
something like that for sure oh yeah
yeah because
then huh if you could redefine the
content
type I
wonder ah but you have to control the
content type header the first time
anyway to get it multi-art mixed because
there's a lot of times where like you're
injecting after the content type
definition and that sort of thing and
you can't override it that's huh
interesting I gotta do I got to do some
more research into that man there's
there my notepad is full yeah you know I
I I have my to-do list today and and
it's like you know record podcast with
Matias and and you know a couple other
things I was getting ready to check this
one off the list but when I check it off
I've got to add like seven additional
items of like go research this and and
document it and put it in thing so thank
you very much for that Matias appreciate
that man um no seriously though it's
been a great episode and um thank you so
much for sharing all your knowledge
about all these different areas and um I
I hereby give you permission in the
future to invite yourself back onto the
Pod whenever you have something
interesting that in your technical
context window so you can get it off
your chest and give it to the world and
uh and that we can all benefit from that
including your own memory having had to
put it into words so that'll be helpful
for everyone involved I
think I that for awesome man great of
course have a good
man
[Music]
yeah